The next aggregate we are going to look at is
the MIN aggregate. The MIN aggregate returns the
lowest number in a list of numbers per group
of columns. Here, we see a query that shows
the sum of sales for each salesperson.
Let's say, within all of these sales,
we want to see the lowest sale
amount as if it is really low,
it may not be worth what it takes to process
the sale. After the SUM line, I will add a comma
and then, on the next line, a MIN aggregate for
the Subtotal column and alias it as 'Lowest Sale'.
We do see some very low sales
here. We have the lowest sale,
but what about the highest sale? For that,
we use the MAX aggregate. I will go back
into the query and add a MAX aggregate for the
Subtotal column and alias it as 'Highest Sale'.
I will execute this, and we see that
some individual sales were rather large.